<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<questions>
	<question>
		<text>Question 1: What is a database?</text>
		<answer>A database is a structured collection of data stored and organized in a way that allows for efficient retrieval, modification, and management of data.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 2: What is MySQL?</text>
		<answer>MySQL is an open-source relational database management system (RDBMS) based on the Structured Query Language (SQL). It is widely used for managing structured data and is known for its performance, reliability, and ease of use.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 3: What is a primary key?</text>
		<answer>A primary key is a unique identifier for each record in a table. It ensures that each record can be uniquely identified and provides a way to enforce data integrity by preventing duplicate or null values in the key field.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 4: What is a foreign key?</text>
		<answer>A foreign key is a field in one table that refers to the primary key in another table. It establishes a relationship between the two tables and enforces referential integrity, ensuring that the values in the foreign key match the values in the primary key.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 5: What is a view?</text>
		<answer>A view is a virtual table that is derived from the result of a SQL query. It does not physically store any data but presents data from one or more tables in a structured manner. Views can be used to simplify complex queries, provide data security, and encapsulate complex logic.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 6: What is normalization?</text>
		<answer>Normalization is the process of organizing data in a database to eliminate redundancy and dependency problems. It involves breaking down a table into multiple tables and establishing relationships between them to minimize data duplication and maintain data integrity.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 7: What is an index?</text>
		<answer>An index is a data structure that improves the speed of data retrieval operations on a database table. It works like the index of a book, allowing the database to quickly locate specific data based on the indexed columns. Indexes can significantly enhance query performance.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 8: What is a stored procedure?</text>
		<answer>A stored procedure is a set of pre-compiled SQL statements stored in the database. It can be called and executed multiple times, providing a way to encapsulate and reuse database logic. Stored procedures enhance performance, security, and modularity of database applications.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 9: What is a trigger?</text>
		<answer>A trigger is a database object that automatically executes a set of SQL statements in response to specific data modifications (inserts, updates, or deletes) on a table. Triggers are often used to enforce complex business rules, maintain data integrity, or perform audit logging.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 10: What is a transaction?</text>
		<answer>A transaction is a logical unit of work that consists of one or more database operations. It follows the ACID (Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability) properties, ensuring that all operations within a transaction are completed successfully or rolled back if any failure occurs.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 11: What is the difference between INNER JOIN and LEFT JOIN?</text>
		<answer>INNER JOIN returns only the matching rows from both tables based on the join condition, whereas LEFT JOIN returns all the rows from the left (first) table and the matching rows from the right (second) table. If there is no match, NULL values are included for the columns of the right table.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 12: What is the difference between CHAR and VARCHAR data types?</text>
		<answer>CHAR is a fixed-length character data type that stores a specific number of characters, padding the remaining space with spaces. VARCHAR is a variable-length character data type that stores a variable number of characters, using only the required storage space without padding.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 13: What is the difference between UNION and UNION ALL?</text>
		<answer>UNION combines the result sets of two or more SELECT statements, eliminating duplicate rows. UNION ALL also combines the result sets but retains all rows, including duplicates. UNION performs additional processing to remove duplicate rows, making it slower than UNION ALL.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 14: What is the difference between DELETE and TRUNCATE?</text>
		<answer>DELETE removes rows from a table based on specified conditions and generates undo logs for possible rollback. TRUNCATE removes all rows from a table without generating undo logs, and it cannot be rolled back. TRUNCATE is faster than DELETE but cannot be used with a WHERE clause.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 15: How can you backup and restore a MySQL database?</text>
		<answer>To backup a MySQL database, you can use the mysqldump command-line utility or tools like phpMyAdmin. To restore a backup, you can use the mysql command-line client or tools like phpMyAdmin to execute the SQL statements from the backup file.</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 16: How do you change the data type of a column in a table?</text>
		<answer>You can use the ALTER TABLE statement with the MODIFY clause to change the data type of a column in a table. For example: ALTER TABLE table_name MODIFY column_name new_data_type;</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 17: How do you add a new column to an existing table?</text>
		<answer>You can use the ALTER TABLE statement with the ADD COLUMN clause to add a new column to an existing table. For example: ALTER TABLE table_name ADD COLUMN new_column_name data_type;</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 18: How do you find the number of rows in a table?</text>
		<answer>You can use the SELECT COUNT(*) statement to retrieve the number of rows in a table. For example: SELECT COUNT(*) FROM table_name;</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 19: How do you sort the result set in descending order?</text>
		<answer>You can use the ORDER BY clause with the DESC keyword to sort the result set in descending order. For example: SELECT * FROM table_name ORDER BY column_name DESC;</answer>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>Question 20: How do you calculate the average value of a column?</text>
		<answer>You can use the AVG() function in conjunction with the SELECT statement to calculate the average value of a column. For example: SELECT AVG(column_name) FROM table_name;</answer>
	</question>
</questions>
